ascendercorp.com 2018-02-25

# Privacy Policy | Monotype

Last updated: January 3, 2017.

Monotype Imaging Holdings Inc., a Delaware corporation with its principal offices at 600 Unicorn Park Drive, Woburn, Massachusetts 01801 USA, and our subsidiaries and affiliates worldwide (collectively, “we”, “us” and/or “our”), make information, products and services available to you directly, on our websites (the “Site(s)”), through app stores, messaging or social network platforms, as well as through other means, all subject to the following Privacy Policy Statement (the "Privacy Statement"). The Privacy Statement applies to all products and services that link to or display this Privacy Statement and/or any Site we own or operate (collectively, the “Services”). By using any of our Services, you agree that we may collect, process, parse, store, retain and use your information, including your personal information, in accordance with this Privacy Statement, as revised from time to time. The Privacy Statement is incorporated by reference into our [Terms of Use](http://www.monotype.com/legal/terms-of-use/).

o Personal information.

o Device information.

o Aggregated usage and statistical information.

* Personal information (information that may be used to readily identify, contact or locate you): 

  * Personal information (information that may be used to readily identify, contact or locate you):   

    * We may collect personal information about you through your use of our Services, such as when you register for our Services, subscribe to receive our communications, update your account information, enter our contests or sweepstakes, respond to surveys, make purchases, contact us with questions or comments, apply for a job, connect with us through social networking platforms, interact with one of our chatbots, submit user generated content or participate in our online forums or promotions, interact with our salespeople, and/or contact our customer service departments.   

      * If, when interacting with one of our Services, you invite third parties to join your account on one of our Services, we may collect all information you provide about those third parties which can include personal information, so you should be sure you have that third parties permission to invite them to join your account, and you should inform them of our privacy practices.
  * Personal information we collect may include: 
    * your full name, username, password, email address, telephone number, physical or billing mail addresses, other information you provide to us when accessing or using one of our Services, and if you have contacted us or accessed one of our Services on behalf of a business or other entity, your professional contact information and any relevant details about your business or entity as it relates to you;
    * information contained in your interactions with one of our chatbots, keystroke information you enter when using one of our mobile applications, comments you may make on one of our forums, attitudes and opinions about and usage of our products that are attributable to you, your demographics, your location, your interests, your professional or lifestyle information, your job description, your level of satisfaction with our Services, your purchasing behavior or history, and your browsing, downloading and other internet- or mobile-based activities;
    * information about you contained in a resume or curriculum vitae, details about yourself that you submit in connection with a job application or inquiry including profile information on any social networking site (for example LinkedIn) if you apply for a job in that manner;
    * information about you that is publicly available or provided by third parties such as information that is posted on social media sites, blogs and other websites; and/or
    * information about you contained in e-mail lists, mailing lists, customer leads, and/or other data we may purchase or obtain from third parties for our advertising and marketing purposes.

We may link information you’ve provided us with other information about you, such as linking your name with your geographic location or your browsing or purchasing history, and we also may Link personal information with information we receive about you from third parties. If we link your personal information with any other information collected or received from you or third parties, we will treat that linked information as personal information. We may ask you to input a credit card number when making a purchase, however all credit card numbers you input through one of our Services are processed and/or stored by a third party credit card or payment facilitator or processor, and not by us.

  * Device information (information about the type of or specific device you use to access our Services): 
    * **Server log files.** An Internet Protocol (“IP”) address is a number automatically assigned to the computer that you are using by your Internet service provider and is identified and logged automatically in our server log files whenever you use certain of our other Services, along with the time of the visit, the page(s) or products that were visited and other information related to your visit. We use IP addresses for purposes such as calculating usage levels, diagnosing server problems, administering our Services, and improving user experiences. We may be able to ascertain your general location through your IP address.
    * **Mobile device identifiers.** We collect your unique device ID, advertising identifier (IDFA, AdID, etc.) and/or other similar data regarding the mobile device you use to access our Services. We may also collect geolocation information from your mobile device.
    * **Cookies and similar technologies.** A cookie is a small text file containing a random and unique alphanumeric identifier that our Services may transfer to your computer's hard drive through your web browser that enable our Services to recognize your browser. We employ technologies like cookies, web beacons, clear GIF, pixel or Internet tag technologies to uniquely identify your account, or the IP address associated with your Internet device. We permit third parties to gather information from our Services, including for advertising purposes. Cookies and the other technologies provide information related to the ways you interact with our advertising or our Services, like browser type, browsing behaviors, user web requests, pages and content viewed, the number of new visits or log-ins, search engine referral, affiliate referrals, traffic driven by banner ads or other promotions, which items are placed in shopping carts and which are abandoned, conversions and what purchases were made. These technologies can contain or store personal and other information (such as if you have previously registered for an account on our Services) and allow web browser servers to recognize return visits to our Services and/or improve web browsing navigation or the quality and delivery of our Services.   

      * Some Cookies, which are known as persistent cookies, remain on your computer or Internet device until you delete them while others, which are known as session cookies, are automatically erased when you exit your Internet browser. You may be able to set your computer or Internet device to accept or reject most Cookies, or to notify you that a Cookie is offered so that you can decide whether to accept it. If you block Cookies, certain features of our Services may not function optimally or at all. Even if you block or delete Cookies, not all tracking will necessarily stop.
    * **Third-party applications and other application programming interfaces.** We offer and deliver certain of our Services through and/or using third party applications, our or third party programming interfaces, extensions that are hosted on our Services or through other third party websites, social and professional networking platforms, and/or messaging platforms. When you Use our Services or otherwise participate in services, products, applications, or connect with or “accept” or “allow” third party applications, networks, platforms or services through our Services, you are authorizing those third parties to receive your information and additionally to potentially share any or all of your information with us, based on your privacy or other settings on that particular third party’s network or platform.
  * Analytical, usage and other statistical information (information that cannot be used to readily identify, contact or locate you): 
    * **De-identified/anonymized information.** We may conduct surveys or collect information that does not uniquely identify you or anyone else. This might include general demographic information like age or income range, gender, education level, profession and other commentary an individual might provide on such survey.
    * **Website and usage information and analytics.** We may work with third-party service or product providers who use the technologies described in this Privacy Statement to conduct website analytics to help us track and understand how visitors use our Sites, such as Google Analytics, Heap or other similar vendors for analytics purposes.
    * **Mobile device and usage information and analytics.** We may work with third party service or product providers and/or third party messaging or social networking platforms to collect data regarding your access to our Services through those platforms, portions of our Services you share through such platforms with other third parties, and/or your navigations through or interactions with our Services on such platforms.

### How do we use the information we collect from you?

We may use the information we collect about you for a variety of purposes, such as to:

  * complete transactions you have requested or fulfill orders you have placed, including orders you may have placed through us with third party font foundries;
  * respond to or follow-up on your comments, reviews, inquiries including product inquiries and other requests;
  * deliver targeted advertising, videos, communications, product solutions, content, and any other information you have requested;
  * conduct research and analysis related to our business or Services;
  * provide third party brands with information about your interaction with our Services as they relate to such third party brands;
  * improve our Services and tailor them to your usage or preferences;
  * communicate with you about contests, sweepstakes, coupons, product and pricing promotions or other matters which you have entered or joined or for which you have requested information;
  * implement social networking features you have activated;
  * publish your reviews, comments, photos, videos and other content you have posted to one of our interactive or user-generated features;
  * communicate with you about your account or your use of our Services, including the delivery of customer service;
  * enforce the terms of use of our Services or otherwise manage our business; and/or
  * send you promotional messages in email or text form that we think will be of interest to you and/or to invite you to events, both in instances where you have opted-in or not opted-out of receiving such messages; or to send you important messages about your use of our Services.

### How and with whom do we share and disclose information we collect from you?

We do not sell or rent your personal information to third parties. From time to time, we may share and/or disclose your personal information with our subsidiaries, affiliates, service providers, partners and other third party business partners (and their service providers), such as in the following examples:

  * to conduct research and/or analysis regarding our Services, market trends and other topics;
  * to third party font foundries from which you may have licensed a font through us so such foundry can provide you customer service, react to your inquiries or solve product issues;
  * to third parties that sponsor our apps or other mobile keyboards;
  * to service providers retained in connection with the provision of some of our Services;
  * to prevent parties from sending promotional messages on our behalf to people who have asked us to not send such messages;
  * if you have opted-in to receive promotional communications from us, send a tailored promotional communications to you jointly offering a product or service; and/or
  * with your specific consent.

We rely on third party service providers to perform a variety of services on our behalf, and we may disclose your personal information to such service providers, for example fulfillment services, business intelligence providers, chatbot providers, ad serving companies, customer service providers, delivery services, e-commerce providers, credit card or payment processers and research and analytics providers. We do not authorize these third parties’ to use your personal information for purposes other than for which it has been provided, and we do not authorize these third parties to disclose that information to unauthorized parties.

If we share your personal information with any third party, we will require such third party to maintain the confidentiality of your personal information, comply with applicable to the sharing of personal information and we will not authorize those third parties to use personal information that we provide for their direct marketing purposes unless we have explicitly given you the option to opt-in or opt-out of that disclosure. If you are a resident of the State of California, you may ask us at any time to refrain from sharing your personal information with third parties for their marketing purposes. Please tell us your preference by contacting us at [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#39494b504f585a4079545657564d40495c175a5654) or by writing to us at:

Monotype Imaging Holdings Inc.  
Attn: Legal Department – Privacy  
600 Unicorn Park Drive  
Woburn, MA 01801 USA

We use and disclose personal information we believe to be necessary or proper: (a) under applicable law, including laws outside your country of residence; (b) to comply with legal or regulator processes; (c) to respond to requests from public and government authorities including public and government authorities outside your country of residence; (d) to enforce our Terms of Use or Terms and Conditions of Business; (e) to protect our and our subsidiaries and affiliates businesses; (f) to protect our rights, privacy, safety or property, and/or that of our subsidiaries and affiliates, you or other third parties; and (g) to allow us to pursue remedies that may be available to us or to limit damages. In addition, we may transfer personal information and other information to a third party in the event of any financing due diligence, bankruptcy, reorganization, merger, sale, joint venture, assignment, transfer or other disposition of all or any portion of our business or assets, or those of our subsidiaries and affiliates.

We may offer community features and public interactive forums through our Services, like discussion boards, chat rooms, forums, wikis, social networking platforms and blogs. When you use these features, your username, posts and other personal information you choose to provide or communicate on these features may be seen by others, and you should think very carefully and exercise extreme caution prior to disclosing any information as information you post could remain viewable in cached or archived webpages or copied and stored by others even after you remove it. We cannot control the actions of others when they use or interact with our Services, and we assume no responsibility for your posts. Furthermore, when you participate in any community features or public interactive forums, you may be agreeing to terms that allow us to use your name and other information you provide via such features in our marketing and advertising.

If the information we collect does not personally identify you, we may use, share and/or disclose such information for any purpose, including sharing such information with third parties, in our sole discretion. Some examples of aggregated, statistical or anonymous information we share with third parties includes:

  * disclosing the number of visitors to our websites;
  * disclosing the number of people who have downloaded a particular communication
  * disclosing the number of people who attended one of our events;
  * disclosing the number of times you have shared a portion of one of our Services with others
  * disclosing where or what else you navigated to or from when interacting with one of our Services; and/or
  * disclosing the number of people from a certain location who have interacted with one of our Services.

Sometimes we partner with other companies to run promotions, joint promotions or offer separate third party promotions. When you provide information for these promotions, you may be providing your information or personal information directly to that third party to use for their own marketing purposes. In those instances, their use of your information including all personal identifiable information will be governed by that third party’s privacy policy, and not this Privacy Statement.

### Do we participate in interest-based advertising programs?

Yes. We may place or recognize a unique cookie on your browser when you access or use some of our Services for the purpose of serving you targeted advertising (also referred to as “online behavioral advertising”). We also allow third-party companies to place their own cookies on your browser when you visit our Services, so that they can collect information, which may include personal information, about your online activities over time and across different sites and serve customized advertisements to you as you browse the Internet.

These third party companies may participate in the Self-Regulatory Program for Online Behavioral Advertising managed by the Digital Advertising Alliance. As part of this program, targeted advertisements may be delivered with an [AdChoices](http://www.aboutads.info/) icon to help you understand how data about you is being used and provide you with the ability to opt-out of that behaviorally targeted advertising. You can click on an [AdChoices](http://www.aboutads.info/) icon to learn more about your choices with respect to interest-based advertising. From a mobile device, you can visit the Digital Advertising Alliance’s [AppChoices website](http://youradchoices.com/appchoices) to download a free app that allows you to set preferences for data collection and use across mobile apps. You can also generally opt-out of receiving personalized ads from third party advertisers and ad networks who are members of the [Network Advertising Initiative](http://www.networkadvertising.org/) by visiting the [opt-out page](http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/) on their website.

Some browsers have a “do not track” feature that allows you to tell websites that you do not want to have your online activities tracked. Only certain of our Services are currently set up to respond to these signals, however, for Services not set up to respond to a “do not track” preference, you have other choices and options as described in this Privacy Statement regarding our different types of advertising and electronic marketing-related communications.

### How can I access and update my personal information?

We will retain personal information for the period necessary to fulfill the purposes outlined in this Privacy Statement unless a longer retention period is required or allowed by law. If you have created an online account on one of our Services and would like to update the personal information you have provided to us, you can access your account on the Service to view and make changes or corrections to your personal information. You may also contact us using the methods described in the “How can you contact us?” section of this Privacy Statement to request access or updates to your information. We will try to comply with your request as soon as reasonably practicable.

### How do I opt-out?

If you no longer want to receive communications from us, you may opt-out of receiving our communications by clicking the "unsubscribe" link at the bottom of any electronic communication you receive from us, or, if you created an online account when you registered to receive our marketing-related communications, you may log-in to your account on the applicable Service and make changes to your communication preferences. If you are having difficulty unsubscribing from our electronic marketing-related communications using the above methods, please contact us directly using the methods listed in the “How can you contact us?” section of this Privacy Statement.

If you no longer want to receive printed communications from us, please contact us directly using the methods listed in the “How can you contact us?” section of this Privacy Statement. In your correspondence, please indicate the nature and types of the communications you no longer wish to receive. Please allow ample time for us to process your request. However, please note that even if you opt-out from receiving certain communications, we may still need to send you communications about your orders, customer service inquiries, promotions participation and other matters. We also may keep information we have collected about you for our records, our research and other purposes.

Also, please note that if you participated in a promotion that involved a third party, and, as part of that promotion, you agreed to receive future marketing communications directly from that party, you will need to contact that party to opt-out of those communications. This process may be outlined in that third party’s privacy policy.

### How do you keep my information secure?

We and certain third parties we employ to collect or store your information use commercially reasonable organizational, technical and administrative means intended to protect collected, provided, stored and/or transmitted information, including your personal information from loss, misuse and unauthorized access or disclosure. However, no method of Internet or electronic transmission or electronic storage is 100% secure or error-free, so we cannot guarantee absolute security.

By using the Services or providing your personal information to us, you agree that we may communicate with you electronically regarding security, privacy and administrative issues relating to your use of the Services. If we learn of a security system breach, we may attempt to notify you electronically by posting a notice on the Services or sending an email to you. You may have a legal right to receive this notice in writing. To receive free written notice of a security breach involving your personal information (or to withdraw your consent from receiving electronic notice), please contact us using the methods listed in the “How can you contact us?” section of this Privacy Statement immediately.

### What Services are not covered by this Privacy Statement?

Some of our Sites and/or Services are operated outside of the United States and are governed by separate privacy policies, which are linked to specifically from those Sites and/or Services.

Some of our Services may contain links or references to other websites or services that are managed by third parties. This Privacy Statement governs only information that we collect through our Services that link to this Privacy Statement, and not to websites, services or applications that do not link to this Privacy Statement or that are maintained and controlled by other companies or organizations, as well as communications from third parties that reference our company or products. For example, our Services offer you the ability to make purchases using third-party payment processor services. In those instances, you will be directed to a webpage that is hosted by the third party (or its service providers) and not by us. Unless otherwise stated, any personal information that you provide through any third party webpage will be collected by that third party, and will be subject to that third party’s privacy policy. We have no control over, and assume no responsibility for any third party’s use of the information you provide to them.

The collection and use of your information by and through third party websites, applications or other means will be governed by the privacy policies applicable to those third parties and mediums. The inclusion of a link or reference on any of our Services does not imply endorsement of the linked site by us or by our subsidiaries and/or affiliates. Websites and other third party products may contain our name, logos, products or other branding even though they are actually operated by third parties that may or may not have a relationship with us. We encourage you to read the privacy statement of every service, application, or website you visit or interact with.

### Do we collect information from children under the age of 13?

We do not knowingly collect, maintain, or use personal information from children under 13 years of age, and no part of the Services is directed to children under the age of 13. Children under 13 should not use our Services and should not provide their personal information to us. If you learn that your child or a child for which you are responsible have provided us with their personal information without your consent, you may alert us at [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#6b1b19021d0a08122b060405041f121b0e45080406). If we learn that we have collected any personal information from any child under 13, we will promptly take steps to delete such information and terminate that child’s account.

### Do we transfer data including across borders?

Because we operate worldwide, your personal information may be stored and/or processed in any country where we have a facility or in which we engage service providers, including in the United States of America or other jurisdictions. By using our Services, you consent to the transfer of information to countries outside your country of residence, including the United States or other jurisdictions which may have different data protection rules than in your country.

If you are visiting from the European Union or other regions with laws governing data collection and use, please note that you are agreeing to the transfer of your information to the United States or other jurisdictions and the processing of your information in the United States as well as other jurisdictions. By providing your information you consent to any transfer and processing in accordance with this Privacy Statement.

By choosing to use the Services or otherwise provide information to us, you agree that any dispute over privacy or the terms contained in this Privacy Statement will be governed by the laws of the Commonwealth of Massachusetts and the adjudication of any disputes arising in connection with the Services will be in accordance with our [Terms of Use](http://www.monotype.com/legal/terms-of-use/).

### How can you contact us?

Please direct any inquiries related to this Privacy Statement, the security of your personal information or other information we have collected about you to our legal department by emailing us at [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#ee9e9c87988f8d97ae838180819a979e8bc08d8183), or by sending mail to:

Monotype Imaging Holdings Inc.  
Attn. Legal Department – Privacy  
600 Unicorn Park Drive  
Woburn, MA 01801 USA

If you have any questions or comments about our company, our Services or have other customer service needs, please contact your local Monotype office. You can [click here for a list of contact information](http://www.monotype.com/company/contact/) for our domestic and international offices.

### Do we make changes to this Privacy Statement and/or to our privacy practices?

Yes. We will update this Privacy Statement from time to time to reflect changes to our practices, the technologies we use that related to your privacy, legal or other regulatory requirements as well as for other reasons. Please check the “LAST UPDATED” notation at the top of this page to see when this Privacy Statement was last revised. When changes are made to this Privacy Statement they will become immediately effective when published in a revised Privacy Statement posted on this page unless otherwise noted. Your use of any of our Services following these changes indicates your consent to the practices described in the revised Privacy Statement.

Also from time to time, we may desire to use your personal information for uses not previously disclosed in this Privacy Statement. If our practices change regarding your previously collected personal information in a way that would be materially less restrictive than stated in the version of this Privacy Statement in effect at the time we collected the information, we will make commercially reasonable efforts to provide notice and obtain your consent for any such uses as may be required by law.
